<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sam Briggs [software developer]</title>
    <link>https://sambriggs.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sam Briggs [software developer]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 14:59:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sambriggs.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Config</title>
      <link>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/python-config/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 22:20:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/python-config/</guid>
      <description>My desire Application configuration, one of the 12 tenets of the 12 factor app  1. Such a reoccurring and important need that it deserves a reusable elegant solution. This blog post assumes you&amp;rsquo;ve already drunk the Kool-Aid. If not perhaps follow the link before proceeding, they&amp;rsquo;ll do a better job than I in convincing you.
From my recent development in Go, I&amp;rsquo;ve become familiar with cobra  and its close relative viper  .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/no-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 21:35:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/no-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>I had a bit of a headscratcher yesterday, as I was writing the Concepts  post and found that my slickly autogenerated architecture diagrams were missing from my posts. Navigating to the image source URLs was giving me the big fat 404 on GitHub pages:
For sanity, I checked out the deploy branch, gh-pages, and sure enough my diagrams were present, nestled in a folder called _gen.
I was immediately suspecious about the leading underscore, and a quick search  of &amp;ldquo;github pages underscore&amp;rdquo; reminded me that GitHub processes deployments with Jekyll unless instructed not to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Device - Choose your weapon(s)</title>
      <link>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/detector-dag/device-choose-your-weapon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 18:48:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/detector-dag/device-choose-your-weapon/</guid>
      <description>With a high-level plan sketched out, it was time to do some &amp;lsquo;part selection&amp;rsquo;.
As someone who&amp;rsquo;s trying to reposition themselves as a &amp;lsquo;backend developer&amp;rsquo;, I knew I wanted to become familiar with AWS&amp;rsquo;s cloud offerings. It might not be the answer to every solution, but it certainly felt like something that should be in my toolkit.
Also, coming from an embedded background, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t fussed about making a bells-and-whistles device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts</title>
      <link>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/detector-dag/concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 11:41:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/detector-dag/concepts/</guid>
      <description>I set to work designing a system for monitoring power remotely, and came up with a few iterations.
All of my concepts revolved around a few assumptions:
 A device would be a cheap Raspberry Pi Zero   There would be a server that could receive staus updates from multiple devices The server would email users in the case of a power failure  Iteration 1: I&amp;rsquo;m alive My initial ideas revolved around connecting the Raspberry Pi to the house&amp;rsquo;s WiFi network:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/detector-dag/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 10:33:44 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/detector-dag/introduction/</guid>
      <description>My latest project was inspired when my best friend&amp;rsquo;s mum came to me with a problem:
 A while back there was a powercut in Alderney1, the circuit breaker tripped, and all the food in our freezer spoiled. Can we find something that will warn us if that has happened, so we can send a neighbour round?
 I felt confident that something would already exist, and sure enough a cursory search turned up a couple of products2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircleCI workspaces</title>
      <link>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/circleci-workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/circleci-workspaces/</guid>
      <description>The problem When I created my CircleCI pipeline in my first post  I came unstuck passing the built site from one job to another as a workspace.
This manifested in two ways, where I&amp;rsquo;d made the same mistake in two different jobs.
Deployment issues The deploy job appeared to work correctly, but when I navigated to the site I was greeted with a 404 error:
HTML-proofer internal link checks And when I ran the htmlproofer tool on my generated site I was greeted with a slew of errors:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://sambriggs.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 14:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sambriggs.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>A mostly-technical blog that records some of the things I find out as I tinker with my software projects.
To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy if all it achieves is saving one person hours of pain having stumbled here chasing an error message via a search engine.
(Hi 👋)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The birth of a blog</title>
      <link>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/the-birth-of-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 14:59:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sambriggs.dev/posts/the-birth-of-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is about how I set up this site!
Framework So I wanted a static site generator. You know, the trendy, &amp;lsquo;lightning-fast&amp;rsquo;, modern-web-has-gone-full-circle technology. Because I just want to write some text that people can read, and I can execute a build step without hurting myself.
 Perfect is the enemy of good
 Knowing I&amp;rsquo;m the kind of person who often lets perfect get the better of me, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to get stuck at step one this time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>